# Alfonso Gonzalez

🛮 alfonso.j.gonzalez@icloud.com 👂 Seattle WA / Rincon PR 🔭 Website 🙀 LinkedIn 🔘 GitHub

### **⋈** SUMMARY

Recent career transition into software engineering after 13 years as an owner and operator of restaurants. Proactive, personable problem solver, eager to put my new skills to work. Fast learner, enjoying the journey into the tech field. I believe that honest and open communication can solve most problems that arise in the workplace. In depth experience in the Ruby and JavaScript ecosystems. Fluent in English and Spanish and able to multi-task and work with a wide range of personality types. I desire a position that provides targeted mentorship to help me expand my skillset and accelerate my ability to take on increasing responsibilities.

# □ LANGUAGES AND TECHNOLOGIES

### • Languages and Frameworks:

JavaScript, Ruby, Node.js, HTML/CSS, SQL, Sinatra, MiniTest, Jekyll, Liquid

# • Technologies:

GitHub, PostgreSQL, Heroku, Sublime

#### PROJECTS

• Todo List, code on GitHub ☑

A tested Heroku application that allows users to create to-do lists. Created using Ruby, Sinatra, and PostgreSQL.

• Tic Tac Toe game, code on GitHub

Simple tic-tac-toe game for the command line created with **Ruby** 

• Rock Paper Scissors game, conde on GitHub

A simple RPS game for a school project created with Ruby

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Owner/Operator, La Isla Cuisine Restaurants

Jan 2005 - Nov 2018

- Hired, trained, and managed multiple teams of employees while building the business from the ground up.
- Seattle

- Created an environment that focused on teamwork, leading by example, and mentorship while encouraging a sense of ownership for my employees.
- Learned to be proactive in solving day-to-day problems that arise in a dynamic environment.

#### **Owner/Operator,** The Valley Cafe Restaurant

Mar 2015 - Oct 2017

• Transitioned into a technology-based system from an analog ticketing system

Ellensburg

• Implemented a training system that taught existing employees to train new hires

# **EDUCATION**

Launch School 🛮

2020 - 2022

• Rigorous mastery-based, multi-year, full-stack software engineering curriculum for programming foundations, object oriented programming, networking and database foundations.

Bachelors degree in Science, University of Massachusetts ☑

1998

**Amherst**